Guide to the Alvin Roth Papers, 1960s-2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Alvin Roth papers 1960s-2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Roth, Alvin E., 1951-
20.1 linear feet Extent: 15075 Items
Roth is the George Gund Professor of Economics and Business Administration at Harvard University. His research interests include game theory, experimental economics, and market design. He won the Nobel Prize in 2012. Collection includes correspondence files, writings and research, writings by other economists, and some teaching material.
RL.01115
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Alvin Roth Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2011.
Biographical and Historical Note
Alvin Roth was born on Dec. 18, 1951. He graduated from Columbia University in 1971, and earned a masters (1973) and Ph.D. (1974) from Stanford University in operations research. Roth went on to teach economics and business administration at the University of Illinois from 1974-1982, and at the University of Pittsburgh from 1982-1998. In 1998, he became full faculty at Harvard University, and remains there today.
Roth's work focuses on game theory, market design, and experimental economics. He has worked on a variety of real-world projects, including the National Resident Matching Program (NRMP) system, responsible for matching medical residents with respective programs; the New York City and Boston public school systems' high school assignment selection methods; and the New England Program for kidney exchanges between incompatible partners. He is a Guggenheim Fellow (1983-1984), an Alfred P. Sloan Research Fellow (1984-1986), and a fellow at the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. He has won the Texas Instruments' Foundation Founders' Prize (1980) and the Operations Research Society of America's Lanchester Prize (1991). In 2012, he and Lloyd Shapley won the Sveriges Riksbank Prize in Economic Sciences in Honor of Alfred Nobel (commonly known as the Nobel Prize) for their work in "the theory of stable allocations and the practice of market design." He has also authored numerous books and over 70 peer-reviewed journal articles.
Collection Overview
The collection offers a wealth of information from Roth's early career at the University of Pittsburgh, including his research and correspondence from that period, as well as drafts of some of his well-cited articles and writings. Approximately one-half of the material lies in the Correspondence and Working Papers series. This portion of the collection, arranged alphabetically by correspondent, includes professional correspondence as well as many drafts of scholarly articles. This arrangement replicates Roth's original filing system, which offers insight into his correspondence style and methodology for economics collaboration. Notable correspondents include Roy Weintraub, Robert Aumann, Ido Erev, Uriel Rothblum, and many more. Also included are various subject files, including Winner's Curse, Matching, and Learning.
Another notable component of the collection is Roth's Writings and Research, which includes both working drafts of Roth's own as well as data printouts and other components of his work in game theory and its real-world applications. These files have been grouped by article and are loosely arranged by date. Each article's co-writers or collaborators are noted if known.
The Writings by Others series has some overlap with the Correspondence and Working Drafts series, but for the most part the former includes only the article from Roth's fellow economists, without the collaborative or feedback aspect present in the latter series.
Roth's Teaching and Coursework series includes lecture notes as well as tools such as transparencies used during his economics lectures. Roth's own coursework at Stanford is also present, including notes, exams, syllabi, and lectures on topics such as microeconomics, competitive strategies, game theory, and choice theory.
Finally, the Grant Materials series is arranged by grant application, with each file including application materials, correspondence, reports, and finances relating to the grant.
Subject Headings
Roth, Alvin E., 1951-; Economics -- Experiments; Economics -- Study and teaching; Econometric models; Matching theory; Kagel, John H. (John Henry), 1942-; Economics -- Methodology; Sotomayor, Marilda A. Oliveira; Game theory; Axiomatic set theory; Negotiation -- Mathematical models; Peranson, Elliott; Slonim, Robert Leonard, 1960-; Nobel Prize winners; Rothblum, Uriel; Aumann, Robert J.; Kagel, John H. (John Henry), 1942-
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence and Working Papers, 1970s-1990s, (12 boxes)
  Roth's files of correspondence and working papers, arranged alphabetically by last name. Files largely consist of professional correspondence between Roth and fellow economists around the world, and usually include copies of a working paper or other scholarship. There are occasional subject files interspersed as well. Most files date from the late 1970s through the early 1990s.
  - Abeledo, Hernán (Box 1)
  - Abreu, Dilip (Box 1)
  - Albers, Wulf (Box 1)
  - Alcalde, Jose (Box 1)
  - Alger, Dan (Box 1)
  - Alkan, Ahmet (Box 1)
  - Anabarci, Nejat M. (Box 1)
  - Arce M., Daniel G. (Box 1)
  - Ashenfelter, Orley (Box 1)
  - Aumann, Robert J. (Box 1)
    Addditional legal-sized correspondence is housed in Box 18.
  - Axelrod, Robert (Box 1)
  - Baiman, Stanley (Box 1)
  - Balinsku, Michel (Box 1)
  - Barbera, Salvador (Box 1)
  - Bartholdi III, John J. (Box 1)
  - Beggs, Alan W. (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Elaine (Box 2)
  - Berg, Joyce E. (Box 2)
  - Bergstrom, Ted (Box 2)
  - Bikhchandani, Sushil (Box 2)
  - Billera, Louis J. (Box 2)
  - Binmore, Kenneth G. (Box 2)
  - Bird, Charles (Box 2)
  - Bjorner, Anders (Box 2)
  - Blair, Charles (Box 2)
  - Bolton, Gary E. (Box 2)
  - Bondareva, O.N. (Box 2)
  - Boorman, Scott (Box 2)
  - Borm, Peter (Pem) (Box 2)
  - Bornstein, Gary (Box 2)
  - Brams, Steven J. (Box 2)
  - Callen, Jeffrey (Box 2)
  - Camerer, Colin F. (Box 2)
  - Carducci, Olivia (Box 2)
  - Carlin, Paul S. (Box 2)
  - Carroll, Wayne (Box 2)
  - Carter, Michael (Box 2)
  - Cashdan, Elizabeth (Box 3)
  - Cave, Jonathan A. K. (Box 3)
  - Caves, Richard E. (Box 3)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Box 3)
  - Chang, Fwu-Rang (Box 3)
  - Chatterjee, Kalyan (Box 3)
  - Chew, Soo Hong (Box 3)
  - Chun, Youngsub (Box 3)
  - Chung, Kim-Sau (Box 3)
  - Chvatal, V. (Box 3)
  - Clark, Herbert H. (Box 3)
  - Collins, Susan (Box 3)
  - Cramton, Peter C. (Box 3)
  - Crane, Fred (Box 3)
  - Crawford, Vincent P. (Box 3)
  - Crott, Helmet (Box 3)
  - David, Paul A. (Box 3)
  - Davis, Morton (Box 3)
  - Debrock, Lawrence M. (Box 3)
  - Driessen, T.S.H. (Box 3)
  - Dubey, Pradeep (Box 4)
  - Durrett, Rich (Box 4)
  - Easley, David (Box 4)
  - Eckel, Catherine (Box 4)
  - Eliashberg, Jehoshua (Box 4)
  - Elster, Jon (Box 4)
  - Englebrecht-Wiggins, R. (Box 4)
  - Erev, Ido (Box 4)
  - Farrell, Joseph von R (Box 4)
  - Felsenthal, Dan S (Box 4)
  - Ferejohn, John A (Box 4)
  - Fiorina, Morris P (Box 4)
  - Forsythe, Robert (Box 4)
  - Friedman, Daniel (Box 4)
  - Fudenberg, Drew (Box 5)
  - Gale, David, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Gal-Or, Esther (Box 5)
  - Gardner, Roy (Box 5)
  - Gauthier, David (Box 5)
  - Geanakoplos, John D. (Box 5)
  - Granot, Daniel (Box 5)
  - Green, Edward (Box 5)
  - Green, Jerry R. (Box 5)
  - Green, Leonard (Box 5)
  - Guggenheim (Box 5)
  - Gul, Faruk (Box 5)
  - Gusfield, Dan (Box 5)
  - Guth, Werner (Box 5)
  - Halpern, Joseph (Box 5)
  - Harrington, Joseph E., Jr. (Box 5)
  - Harrison, Glenn W. (Box 6)
  - Harsanyi, John C. (Box 6)
  - Harstad, Ronald (Box 6)
  - Hart, Sergiu (Box 6)
  - Heckathorn, Douglas (Box 6)
  - Heijmans, Johannes (Box 6)
  - Herrero, Maria-Jose (Box 6)
  - Hoffman, Elizabeth, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Holland, Paul W. (Box 6)
  - Holmstrom, Bengt (Box 6)
  - Holt, Charles A. (Box 6)
  - Howe, Eric D. (Box 6)
  - Huang, Peter H. (Box 6)
  - Hwang, J.S. (Box 6)
  - Imai, Haruo (Box 6)
  - Jaycees-TOYM (Ten Outstanding Young Men) (Box 7)
  - Jones, Philip C. (Box 7)
  - Kagel, John H. (Box 7)
  - Kahn, Charles (Box 7)
  - Kahneman, Daniel (Box 7)
  - Kalai, Ehud (Box 7)
  - Kamecke, Ulrich (Box 7)
  - Kaneko, Mamoru (Box 7)
  - Kihlstrom, Richard (Box 7)
  - Kikuta, Kensaku (Box 7)
  - Kim, Yong-Gwan (Box 7)
  - Knez, Marc J. (Box 7)
  - Knuth, Donald E. (Box 7)
  - Kohli, Rajeev (Box 7)
  - Kreps, David M. (Box 7)
  - Kulakovskaja, T.E. (Box 7)
  - Landsberger, Michael (Box 7)
  - Laskey, Kathryn B. (Box 7)
  - Learning (subject) (Box 7)
  - Lehrer, Ehud (Box 8)
  - Leopold-Wildburger, Ulrike (Box 8)
  - Levin, Dan (Box 8)
  - Lipman, Barton L. (Box 8)
  - Loomes, Graham (Box 8)
  - Lucas, William F. (Box 8)
  - Matching (subject) (Box 8)
  - Machina, Mark (Box 8)
  - Malkiel, Burton G. (Box 8)
  - Mandel, Michael J. (Box 8)
  - Marshall, Robert C. (Box 8)
  - Maskin, Eric (Box 8)
  - Masso, Jordi (Box 8)
  - McClennan, Edward (Box 8)
  - McMillan, John (Box 8)
  - Mertens, Jean-Francois (Box 8)
  - Michener, H. Andrew (Box 8)
  - Milgrom, Paul R. (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Mo, Jie-Ping, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Moldovanu, Benny (Box 8)
  - Mortensen, Dale T. (Box 8)
  - Moulin, Herve (Box 8)
  - Murnighan, Keith (Box 8)
  - Myerson, Roger B. (Box 8)
  - Nagle, Rosemarie (Box 8)
  - Neale, Margaret (Box 8)
  - Neelin, Janet (Box 8)
  - Norman, Robert Z. (Box 9)
  - Nydegger, Rudy V. (Box 9)
  - O’Brien, John R. (Box 9)
  - Ochs, Jack (Box 9)
  - Okada, Akira (Box 9)
  - Okuno, Masahiro (Box 9)
  - O’Neill, Barry (Box 9)
  - Osborne, Martin J. (Box 9)
  - Ostrom, Elinor (Box 9)
  - Palfrey, Thomas R. (Box 9)
  - Peleg, Belazel (Box 9)
  - Pittel, Boris (Box 9)
  - Plott, Charles R. (Box 9)
  - Pollak, Robert A. (Box 9)
  - Pondy, Louis R. (Box 9)
  - Postlethwaite, Andrew (Box 9)
  - Prudencio, Yves Coffi (Box 9)
  - Publishers' correspondence, 1984-1998 (Box 9)
  - Quint, Thomas (Box 9)
  - Quinzii, Martine (Box 9)
  - Radner, Roy (Box 9)
  - Raiffa, Howard (Box 9)
  - Rapoport, Amnon (Box 9)
  - Rapoport, Anatol (Box 9)
  - Rashid, Salim (Box 9)
  - Rietz, Thomas A. (Box 9)
  - Reny, Philip J. (Box 9)
  - Rice, Peter (Box 10)
  - Rob, Rafael (Box 10)
  - Roberts, John (Box 10)
  - Rochford, Sharon (Box 10)
  - Romero-Medina, Antonio (Box 10)
  - Ronn, Eytan (Box 10)
  - Rosen, Sherwin (Box 10)
  - Rosenthal, Robert W. (Box 10)
  - Roter, V.I. (Box 10)
  - Roth, Ted (Box 10)
  - Rothblum, Uriel G., (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Rubin, Jeffrey Z. (Box 10)
  - Rubinstein, Ariel (Box 10)
  - Samet, Dov (Box 10)
  - Samuelson, Larry (Box 10)
  - Samuelson, William (Box 10)
  - Schmeidler, David (Box 10)
  - Schotter, Andrew (Box 11)
  - Schoumaker, Francoise (Box 11)
  - Scotchmer, Suzanne (Box 11)
  - Segal, Uziel (Box 11)
  - Selten, Reinhard (Box 11)
  - Sen, Amartya (Box 11)
  - Shaked, Avner (Box 11)
  - Shannon, Chris (Box 11)
  - Shapiro, Roy D. (Box 11)
  - Shapley, Lloyd S. (Box 11)
  - Shenoy, P.P. (Box 11)
  - Shmida, Avi (Box 11)
  - Shubik, Martin (Box 11)
  - Siegel, Sidney (Box 11)
  - Sloan Foundation (Box 11)
  - Smith, Lones (Box 11)
  - Smith, Vernon L. (Box 11)
  - Sobel, Joel (Box 11)
  - Sondak, Harris (Box 11)
  - Sonmez, Tayfun (Box 11)
  - Sonnenschein, Hugo (Box 11)
  - Sopher, Barry (Box 11)
  - Sprague, John (Box 11)
  - Stahl, Dale O. (Box 11)
  - Steinberg, Richard (Box 11)
  - Straffin, Philip D. (Box 12)
  - Subramanian, Ashok (Box 12)
  - Sunder, Shyam (Box 12)
  - Sussangkarn, Chal (Box 12)
  - Tauman, Yair (Box 12)
  - Technion (Box 12)
  - Telser, Lester G. (Box 12)
  - Texas Instruments (Box 12)
  - Thaler, Richard (Box 12)
  - Thomson, William (Box 12)
  - Tietz, Reinhard (Box 12)
  - Tijs, S.H. (Box 12)
  - Tucker, A.W. (Box 12)
  - USIP (U.S. Institute of Peace) (Box 12)
  - Van Damme, Eric (Box 12)
  - Vande Vate, John (Box 12)
  - Verrecchia, Robert (Box 12)
  - Vilkas, Eduardas (Box 12)
  - Villamil, Anne P. (Box 12)
  - Wako, Jun (Box 12)
  - Weber, Robert James (Box 12)
  - Weintraub, Roy (Box 12)
  - Winner’s Curse (subject) (Box 12)
  - Winship, Christopher (Box 12)
  - Winter, Eyal (Box 12)
  - Wolinsky, Asher (Box 12)
  - Wooders, M. Holtz (Box 12)
  - Young, H.P. (Box 12)
  - Yuan, Yufei (Box 12)
  - Zame, William R. (Box 12)
  - Zamir, Shmuel (Box 12)
  - Zhou, Lin (Box 12)
  - Zoffer, H.J. (Box 12)
  - Aumann, Robert (Box 18)
  - Handbook of Experimental Economics, 1988-1991 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence 1983-1986 (Box 25)
- Writings and Research, 1969-1998, (10 boxes)
  Drafts, correspondence, and data from a selection of Roth's many journal articles. Includes correspondence between Roth and his co-writers, as well as some publishers' correspondence. Arranged loosely by date, although many articles span several years and thus do not fit in a precise chronological order. Also included at the end of the series are research and notes on game theory.
  - Roth: Electrostatic Charge on Aircraft in Flight, 1969 (Box 13)
  - Roth: Self-Supporting Equilibria in the Supergame, 1975 (Box 13)
  - Roth: A Note on Cooperative Games with Varying Power, 1975 (Box 13)
  - Roth: Interpersonal Comparisons and Equal Gains in Bargaining, 1978 (Box 13)
  - Roth: Values for Games without Sidepayments: Some Difficulties with Current Concepts, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Roth: Axiomatic Models of Bargaining, 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Roth: An Impossibility Result Concerning n-Person Bargaining Games, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Kihlstrom, Roth, and Schmeidler: Risk Aversion and Solutions to Nash's Bargaining Problem, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Roth and Malouf: Game Theoretic Models and the Role of Information in Bargaining, 1979, (Folder 1 of 3) (Box 13)
  - Roth and Malouf: Game Theoretic Models and the Role of Information in Bargaining, 1979-1982, (Folders 2-3 of 3) (Box 14)
  - Roth: Further Analysis of the Resident Match, 1981 (Box 22)
  - Roth: On the Non-Transferable Utility Value: A Reply to Aumann, 1981-1984, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Roth: The National Resident Matching Program: An Organizational Analysis from a Game-Theory Perspective, 1982 (Box 22)
  - Roth: Conflict and Coincidence of Interest in Job Matching: Some New Results and Open Questions, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Roth and Murnighan: Information and Aspirations in Two Person Bargaining, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Roth and DeBrock: The Rules of the Game: Labor Management Negotiations and Major League Baseball, 1983-1985 (Box 22)
  - Roth: The College Admissions Problems is Not Equivalent to the Marriage Problem, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Roth: Common and Conflicting Interests in Two-Sided Matching Markets, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Roth: Misrepresentation and Stability in the Marriage Problem, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Roth: A Note on Risk Aversion in a Perfect Equilibrium Model of Bargaining, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Ochs and Roth: A Further Comment on Experimental Economics: "Privacy" as an Experimental Condition, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Roth: Further Thoughts on the Power of Alternative: An Example from Labor-Management Negotiations in Major League Baseball, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Roth: Game Theory and Experimental Economics, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Roth: Laboratory Experimentation in Economics, 1985-1986 (Box 22)
  - Roth: On the Allocation of Residents to Rural Hospitals: A General Property of Two-Sided Matching Markets, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Roth: Some Additional Thoughts on Post-Settlement Settlements, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Roth and Sotomayor: Interior Points in the Core of Two-Sided Matching Markets, 1985-1987 (Box 22)
  - Roth: Mutual Restraint in Tree Swallows: Reinterpretation of the Data and Remarks on the Empirical Testing of Game-Theoretic Models, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Roth and Mongell: A Note on Job Matching with Budget Constraints, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Roth: On the Non-transferable Utility Value: A Reply to Aumann, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Roth and Sotomayor: The College Admissions Problem Revisited, 1987 (2 folders) (Box 22)
  - Murnighan, Roth, Schoumaker: Risk Aversion in Bargaining: An Experimental Study, 1987 (Box 22)
  - Roth: Axiomatic Models of Bargaining and Related Strategic Models and Experimental Evidence, 1988 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 23)
  - Roth: "Common, Conflicting Interests in Two-Sided Matching Markets", included in Game Theory and Applications vol., 1988 (Box 23)
  - Roth et al: The Deadline Effect in Bargaining: Some Experimental Evidence, 1988, (3 folders) (Box 23)
  - Roth: Laboratory Experiments in Economics: A Methodological Overview, 1988 (Box 23)
  - Roth: National Science Foundation Proposal (rejected), 1988 (Box 14)
  - Roth: Risk Aversion in Multi-Person Bargaining over Risky Agreements, 1988 (Box 23)
  - Roth and Ochs: An Experimental Study of Sequential Bargaining, 1988-1989, (2 folders) (Box 23)
  - Roth and Sotomayor: Handbook of Game Theory with Economic Applications- chapter on matching, 1988-1989 (Box 23)
  - Roth and Vate: Random Paths to Stability in Two-Sided Matching, 1988-1989 (Box 23)
  - Roth: Risk Aversion and the relationship between Nash's solution and subgame perfect equilibrium of sequential bargaining, 1988-1989 (Box 23)
  - Roth: "Handbook"/ Bazerman manuscript collaboration, 1989 (Box 23)
  - Roth and Mongell: Sorority Rush as a Two-Sided Matching Mechanism, 1989 (Box 23)
  - Roth: Two-Sided Matching with incomplete information About Others' Preferences, 1989 (Box 23)
  - Roth and Kagel: Comment on Harrison vs. Cox, Smith, and Walker: Theory and Misbehavior in First-Price Auctions, 1990 (Box 23)
  - Roth: Game Theory as a part of Empirical Economics, 1990 (Box 23)
  - Roth: Let's Keep the Con out of Experimental Econ: A Methodological Note, 1990 (Box 23)
  - Roth and Vate: Incentives in Two-Sided Matching with Random Stable Mechanisms, 1990 (Box 23)
  - Roth: A Natural Experiment in the Organization of Entry Level Labor Markets: Regional Markets for New Physicians in the UK, 1990 (Box 25)
  - Roth, et al: Bargaining and Market Behavior in Jerusalem, Ljubljana, Pittsburgh, and Tokyo: An Experimental Study, 1990-1991, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Roth and Prasnikar: Considerations of Fairness and Strategy: Experimental Data from Sequential Games, 1990-1991, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Maulitz and Fox: The Bureau of Health Professions: An Analytical History, 1991 (Box 24)
  - Mongell and Roth: Figures from AER article, 1991 (Box 14)
  - Roth and Sotomayor: Stable Outcomes in Discrete and Continuous Models of 2-sided Matching, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
  - Roth and Kagel: Handbook of Experimental Economics, 1992 (Box 24)
  - Prasnikar and Roth: Considerations of Fairness and Strategy (graphics for Quarterly Journal of Economics), 1992 (Box 18)
  - Roth: Adaptive Behavior and Strategic Rationality - Torino Conference, 1992-1993 (Box 15)
  - Roth and Xing: "Jumping the Gun: Imperfections and Institutions Related to the Timing of Market Transactions", 1992-1993 (Box 24)
  - Roth: Keep Con out of Experimental Econ, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Roth: "On the Early History of Economics", 1993 (Box 24)
  - Kagel and Roth: The Dynamics of Reorganization in Matching Markets, 1993-1997, (4 folders) (Box 16)
  - Slonim and Roth: Financial Incentives and Learning in Ultimatum and Market Games: An Experiment in the Slovak Republic, 1993-1994, (Folder 1 of 6) (Box 16)
  - Roth: Bargaining Experiments reprint permissions, 1994 (Box 24)
  - Roth: Individual Rationality as Useful Approximation - Tversky's Rational Theory and Constructive Choice, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Roth and Kagel: Handbook of Experimental Economics, 1994-1998, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Roth and Xing: Turnaround Time and Bottlenecks in Market Cleaning, 1994-1996, (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - Roth and Erev: Learning in Extensive-Form Games: Experimental Data and Simple Dynamic Models in the Intermediate Term, 1995, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Roth and Erev: Reinforcement Learning in Experimental Games..., 1995-1997, (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - Roth: Market for Federal Judicial Law Clerks - Lessons Learned, 1995 (Box 15)
  - Slonim and Roth: Financial Incentives and Learning in Ultimatum and Market Games: An Experiment in the Slovak Republic, 1995-1997, (Folders 2-6 of 6) (Box 17)
  - Roth and Rothblum: Truncation Strategies in Matching Markets, 1995-1998, (3 folders) (Box 16)
  - Roth, Blum, Rothblum: "Vacancy Chains: Equilibrium in Senior-Level Labor Markets", 1996, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Roth and Peranson: Effects of Change in the NRMP Algorithm, 1996-1997, (3 folders) (Box 15)
  - Roth and Sotomayor: Existence of Stable Outcomes for an Unified Matching Market, 1997 (Box 16)
  - Erev and Roth: Predicting How People Play Games: Reinforcement Learning in Experimental Games, 1997 (Box 25)
  - Peranson and Roth: Redesign of Matching Market for American Physicians, 1997 (Box 25)
  - Roth and Rothblum: Truncation Strategies in Matching Markets- In Search of Advice for Participants, 1997 (Box 25)
  - Kagel and Roth: The dynamics of reorganization in matching markets: A laboratory experiment..., 1997-1998 (Box 25)
  - Roth, Erev, Slonim: Learning and equilibrium as useful approximations, 1998 (Box 25)
  - Slonim and Roth: Learning in High Stakes Ultimatum Games- An Experiment in the Slovak Republic, 1998 (Box 25)
  - Roth: Truncation Strategies in Matching Markets- In Search of Advice for Participants; with Rothblum, 1998 (Box 25)
  - Roth: Cooperative Games, undated (Box 17)
  - Roth: Evolutionary Stable Strategies, undated (Box 17)
  - Roth: Games with infeasible computations, undated (Box 25)
  - Roth: Instructions on Risk Aversion simulation printouts, undated (Box 17)
  - Erev and Roth: Learning, reciprocation, and the value of bounded rationality, undated (Box 25)
  - Roth: National Resident Matching Program Algorithm, undated (Box 25)
  - Roth: Stability and Polarization of Interests in Job Matching, undated (Box 25)
  - Research and notes (Box 18)
    - Game theory (Box 18)
    - Game theory experiment print-outs, (3 folders) (Box 18)
  - Two economic texts in Yiddish (Box 20)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1980s-1990s (Box 25)
  - Navy Personnel Recruitment documentation, 1983-1984 (Box 25)
  - AMCAS- Medical School Application Procedures, 1984 (Box 25)
  - NRMP Collaborations and Correspondence, 1985 (Box 25)
  - NRMP Directories, (2 folders) (Box 25)
  - NRMP Notes (Box 25)
- Writings by Others, 1973-1997 and undated, (2 boxes)
  Drafts and articles sent to Roth but written by other economists. Files are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Aumann, Robert J. (Box 19)
    - An Axiomatization of the Non-Transferable Utility Value, 1983 (Box 19)
    - One the NTU Value (Box 19)
    - Power and Public Goods (Box 19)
    - Rejoinder (Box 19)
    - Value, Symmetry, and Equal Treatment (Box 19)
  - Bendor and Swistak: Evolutionary stability of cooperation, 1998 (Box 19)
  - Billera, Louis J.
    - A Characterization of Polyhedral Market Games (Box 19)
    - On Games without Side Payments Arising from a General Class of Markets, 1973 (Box 19)
    - Market Representations of n-Person Games, 1973 (Box 19)
  - Board, Raymond
    - Decentralized Decision-Making in Two-Sided Matching, 1992 (Box 19)
    - Measuring the Instability in Two-Sided Matching Procedures, 1993 (Box 19)
  - Burrows, Paul, and Graham Loomes: The Impact of Fairness on Bargaining Behavior, 1992 (Box 19)
  - Friedman, Eric, 1996-1997 (Box 19)